[♪ theme music playing]
THE HUSBAND
THIS SERIES IS FICTITIOUS
CHILDREN WERE FILMED SAFELY
GEN AI WAS USED IN SELECT SCENES
FINAL EPISODE
[♪ mysterious music playing]
You awake?
[inhales] Where is Ms. Kim Gyeongae?
[snaps fingers]
Where did you hide her?
I said I'd do her surgery.
You're not needed anymore.
I can do the surgery.
You?
You can only operate
with adult stem cells.
It's likely to fail.
[sighs]
[Dr. Choi] I'll do the surgery,
using fetal stem cells.
It's all in my car.
Everything's set up.
[Taeju] So you're saying
you'll operate on her, with your skills?
I don't think
you fully understand this situation.
[chuckles] Are you that confident?
Adult or fetal,
can you pull off the surgery?
[♪ tense music playing]
[sighs]
Where's my wife?
THE HUSBAND
[sighs]
I ought to kill those scumbags.
You trust that guy
after all that I've told you?
I don't trust him.
I'm just weighing my options.
STYLE
::cue()
One of you will save my wife.
PYEONGWON FUNERAL HOME
PYEONGWON NURSING HOME
[seat belt unbuckles]
[phone buzzes]
-Get out.
-[seat belt unbuckles]
[Manhui] Wait a minute.
You said you've got
the fetal stem cells ready.
Go get it.
-[trunk opens]
-[object thudding]
It's all cultured.
We can save your wife with--
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[sighs]
Go.
[door opens]
[car chimes]
[keys rattling]
Honey. [gasps]
Gyeongae.
Honey. [panting]
Honey.
Gyeongae.
[gasps] Honey.
Yeah, it's me. I'm here.
I'm right here.
-Noh Manhui.
-Yes, it's me.
[breathes shakily]
I'm here.
What took you so damn long?
I told you to come back for me soon.
I'm sorry it took so long.
I'm here for you.
[both breathing heavily]
What are those people doing here?
Why did you come with them?
[sniffs, exhales]
You don't need him anymore, right?
You just need me for the surgery.
-Honey.
-[Manhui] Yeah, it's okay.
[♪ tense music playing]
STYLE
::cue()
Huh?
[syringe cap clicks, clatters]
[cap clatters]
[♪ music intensifies]
[Dr. Choi] Finish him off.
With your own hands.
Don't you want to save your wife?
What… What are you doing?
What are you doing?
-[straining] You…
-[grunting]
[both grunting]
Look at this.
SURGERY SUCCESS RATE: 13%
You're going to save my wife
with these kinds of odds?
-Huh? Huh?
-[grunts]
You bastard. Huh?
-No…
-[screams]
-[grunts]
[gasps]
[panting]
[groaning, panting]
[grunts]
[panting]
[sighs]
Huh?
Damn it.
[panting]
CLINICAL TRIAL REPORT
DR. CHOI CHIUNG
Why did you stop me? Huh?
[shouting] Why did you stop me? [panting]
You shouldn't do this anymore.
That guy tried to kill my wife, okay?
He also made me kidnap yours
and tried to have you killed too!
Yeah, I know.
You do?
That bastard was going to kill my wife!
So?
You're going to kill him now?
That's pretty convenient.
It's okay to kill
as long as you've got a cause, right?
But you know what?
I want to kill you just as much.
Every time I look at you,
I think of my wife.
And how terrible it must've been
to be locked up in there, and how…
How painful it must have been.
The thought alone
damn near drives me insane.
But I won't kill you.
And that's not because I can't.
SURGERY SUCCESS RATE: 13%
Who's that from?
Cha Myeonghui.
STYLE
::cue()
Long time no see.
How have you been?
But where are you off to in such a hurry,
Dr. Cha Myeonghui?
Choi Chiung had me fooled as well.
I wanted to save your wife too.
I swear I mean it.
There's
still one thing I can do.
[Gyeongae screaming]
-Honey.
-[Gyeongae grunting]
Honey.
-Honey, are you okay?
-[screaming, grunting continues]
Ms. Kim, can you feel your legs?
-[Gyeongae panting]
-Can you?
I need an answer now.
I can't feel them.
The tumor's compressing
her spinal cord again.
If we leave her like this,
she'll be paralyzed from the waist down.
[Gyeongae groaning]
You can save her, right?
If we operate right now.
And her spinal cord
needs to be reconstructed,
and it needs to be done now.
No way.
I don't want to put my life in his hands.
-Gyeongae.
-[Gyeongae] Honey.
I don't want to do this anymore.
Honey, no!
I am not going to owe that man my life.
It's not like that at all, okay?
I'll owe him and I'll pay for it. Okay?
And you just have to make it through this.
You understand?
Damn it, this hurts so bad.
[pocket knife opens]
There.
You do the surgery.
Everything Choi Chiung put me up to,
everything I did…
I have all the evidence you need.
Just do the surgery,
and I'll hand over all of it
and turn myself in.
And so…
you better keep your word too.
[breathing heavily]
Yeah, I will.
I'll do the surgery. She's a patient.
But that doesn't mean I forgive you.
I'm not doing it out of mercy,
but because I'm a doctor.
You will pay for what you did.
STYLE
::cue()
We have to move her immediately.
Honey.
-[groaning]
-Gyeongae, careful.
[panting, groaning]
[car chimes]
MISSED CALLS: SEYUN
[dialing]
[line ringing]
[Dr. Ko] Hello?
Father, it's me.
I need to perform
an emergency surgery right now.
What?
What emergency surgery?
What the hell are you talking about?
I need an OR prepped with a small team
of trusted staff members.
Wait. Who needs this emergency surgery?
-It's Kim Gyeongae.
-What?
What… Why are you operating on her?
Father, I'll fill you in
on the details afterward.
-Please just do this for me.
-[sighs]
I understand.
I'll have it arranged.
Great, thank you.
[call ends]
[dialing]
[phone buzzes]
-Hello?
-Hey, honey.
Where are you right now?
Why was your phone switched off?
I'm so sorry. Something urgent came up.
-What happened?
-Hey, Seyun.
Uh, could you stay
over at your parents' for now?
Why would I do that?
[inhales] Taeju.
What's going on?
You're not in danger again, are you?
No, I'm not. It's nothing like that.
[sighs] Tell me what's going on then.
You know, it's just…
With all that's been happening recently,
I just have this weird feeling today.
I'd just feel more at ease
if you'd stay with your parents.
[sighs] Okay.
But, Taeju.
Yeah.
Don't try to shoulder it all alone again.
I know by now
that things are at their worst
when you don't say anything.
I'll be fine.
Okay. Bye.
[call ends]
[sighs]
STYLE
::cue()
PYEONGWON FUNERAL HOME
PYEONGWON NURSING HOME
EMERGENCY ROOM
[breathing heavily]
[grunts]
[panting]
Hey. She's in that car.
[doctor 1] All right, ma'am. Here we go.
-[Gyeongae groaning]
-[doctor 2] Careful.
[doctor 1] Ma'am, one step at a time now.
Careful. Watch it.
[groaning continues]
-Here.
-[doctor 1] Lean on the bed.
-There.
-[doctor 3] Watch your back.
[groaning continues]
-[doctor 3] Okay, just a bit more.
-[doctor 2] Here we go.
[Manhui] Honey.
You'll be all better after this surgery.
Wait for me, okay?
I'll be right here.
Okay.
[breathes shakily]
Save her.
Please.
[Taeju] I'm going to do what I have to do.
You should think long and hard
about what it is you should do too.
AUTHORIZED PERSONNEL ONLY
RESTRICTED AREA
[Gyeongae] I've got to say,
we can't seem to get rid of each other.
Isn't it funny?
Having to save someone you hate to death
with your own hands twice.
But please do it.
I want to live.
You're a doctor.
Ready to start anesthesia.
[anesthesiologist] Yes, Doctor.
[equipment hissing]
STYLE
::cue()
[heart monitor beeping]
[Taeju] All right, let's begin.
Ten blade, please.
The tumor margins are visible.
Bipolar.
Tumor forceps, please.
[instruments clinking]
[sighs]
Open the scaffold, please.
-BP's dropping, Doctor. 85 over 55.
-[machines beeping]
[nurse] We're seeing increased bleeding.
[Taeju] Suction.
What's going on? [gasps]
[breathing shakily]
Bipolar.
-Keep the suction on.
-Yes, Doctor.
Phenylephrine.
[anesthesiologist] Push the phenylephrine.
[exhales]
Okay, wide open on the IV fluids.
Get another unit of PRBCs on standby.
[anesthesiologist] One more unit.
Honey.
[nurse] Bleeding is controlled.
Vitals are stabilizing.
-What's our total blood loss so far?
-We're past 250 ccs, Doctor.
Okay, we're good.
Let's continue.
Suture, please.
STYLE
::cue()
SEONGJIN POLICE STATION
SAFE SEONGJIN, TRUSTED POLICE
-Captain.
-[in English] Oh, thank you.
[sighs]
[in Korean] How can I…
Captain.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
Ms. Cha Myeonghui.
I'm ready…
to tell you everything.
-[door opens]
-[bell chimes]
Welcome in.
[bottle opens]
Oh, gosh. Excuse me.
You haven't paid for that.
-Give me a break.
-[sighs]
Oh, dear. Excuse me!
You have to pay first!
My goodness. I get you're thirsty,
but you have to pay first.
Goodness me.
[Dr. Choi sighs]
Go ahead. Ring me up.
[register beeps]
[owner] That'll be 7,300 won.
[sighs] Hey.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
Let me borrow your car.
SIWON CONVENIENCE STORE
Please help.
[heart monitor beeping]
Dr. Yoon, could you get
the monitoring room on the line?
Yes, Doctor.
You're patched in.
[PA system beeps]
[Taeju] Can you hear me?
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
I'm keeping my promise.
It's your turn now.
The evidence you said you had on you.
Send everything over
to Captain Jang Dosik at Seongjin PD.
I will once you're finished.
No, do it right now.
Finish the surgery first.
I think you're forgetting…
that your wife's life
is in my hands right now.
The longer you hesitate,
the fewer options I'm left with here.
[Manhui] Are you
threatening me right now?
[Taeju] Yeah, using your exact playbook.
Using people's fear of losing
their loved ones to control them.
That's what you're best at.
Send it. Right now.
STYLE
::cue()
Have you spoken to Dr. Choi
on the phone lately?
No.
[Detective Oh]
So you haven't talked to him.
Captain, we're unable
to locate Choi Chiung.
He's not at home,
and his phone's turned off.
[sighs]
Keep looking.
Yes, sir.
[phone buzzes]
MESSAGES
NEW MESSAGE
What the hell?
RECORDINGS
[Dr. Choi]
With Kang Taeju out of the picture,
the director will
eventually stop holding out
and resume the project.
[Manhui]
You're saying if we got rid of him,
you could save my wife, right?
[Dr. Choi] Yes.
Get Kang Taeju out of the picture,
and I promise,
I'll save your wife's life at all costs.
[phone buzzes]
WRITTEN CONFESSION
NAME: NOH MANHUI
I, NOH MANHUI, HEREBY CONFESS
TO THE SERIES OF CRIMES…
[sighs]
[door opens]
[Dr. Ko] How's Dr. Kang's surgery going?
Is everything all right?
Let me know if anything comes up.
Yeah, okay.
-[call ends]
-[door opens]
What surgery are you talking about?
Seyun.
Who is Taeju operating on right now?
Well, that's…
Dad!
[dialing]
Detective Jang, it's Ko Seyun.
[heart monitor beeping]
I sent it.
[breathing heavily]
You little…
RESTRICTED AREA
What the hell, man?
I did everything as you said!
What the hell's going on?
The surgery's over.
[breathing shakily] What?
The surgery is done.
The tumor's out,
and the reconstruction's done.
Surgery was a success.
Your wife's going to make it.
Are you sure?
We were already done closing her up
before you even sent the files over.
All right, your wife is safe now.
So you'd better keep your word.
STYLE
::cue()
[car chimes]
[breathing heavily]
Chiung.
Ms. Ko.
What are you doing here this early?
Something urgent came up.
You sure you're not here to see Taeju?
How did the surgery go?
So he's gone and done it.
It's Kang Taeju again.
It's always been like this.
He always gets to do it in the end.
I'm the one who found them.
I waited all that time.
And I prepared everything. I did it all!
[♪ dramatic music playing]
But it's always him holding the scalpel.
You know whose fault that is?
It's yours, Ms. Ko.
You're the one
who brought him to this hospital.
[sighs]
Yeah.
This is all your fault, Ko Seyun.
Chiung.
You're out of your mind.
No.
I finally see things for what they are.
Today, you
and your husband…
You're both dead.
-[grunting]
-[screams]
-[panting, grunting]
-[straining]
[Seyun screaming]
[Dr. Choi screams]
[groaning, panting]
[breathing heavily]
[door opens]
[elevator chimes]
-[electronic voice] The doors are opening.
-[Dosik] Choi Chiung!
You're not getting to my husband!
[screams]
-[thuds]
-[wheezing]
-[Dosik] Ms. Ko!
-Hold him down.
[Hyeonsu] Mr. Choi, you are under arrest
for solicitation of kidnapping and murder.
-You have the right to stay silent…
-[Dosik] Ms. Ko!
-…and the right to an attorney.
-Requesting medical support!
-[Hyeonsu] If you can't afford one,
one will be provided for you.
STYLE
::cue()
Gyeongae.
It's all over.
What are you doing?
Put the knife down.
She's alive.
That's all that matters.
I sent over the files.
They should have everything they need now.
One thing.
My wife's name isn't on there.
I'm taking all the blame and ending this.
Put it down.
We can talk this out.
Stay away.
If you die, what about your wife?
You think she'll be happy without you
as if none of this ever happened?
She'll manage.
No, stop lying to yourself.
You're just running away.
You're taking the easy way out.
You killed all those people,
claiming it was to save your wife,
and now you're using her
as an excuse to kill yourself?
Hey, look.
You're being a coward.
You're being selfish.
If you die here…
your wife has to take the fall
for all your crimes.
Then what?
What am I supposed to…
What am I supposed to do? Huh?
Live.
And take accountability.
I can't.
I can't do that to my Gyeongae.
I can't let her live
her whole life as a criminal.
Absolutely no way.
I'm sorry, honey.
[both grunt]
Let go.
I said let go!
I can't let you and your wife
get off that easy.
Live and pay for your crimes.
[Taeju groaning]
Noh Manhui, drop the knife! Get him!
Mr. Kang! Come here!
Mr. Noh, you're under arrest
for kidnapping and murder.
You have the right to remain silent
and the right to an attorney.
If you can't afford one,
one will be provided for you.
STYLE
::cue()
[sighs]
Mr. Kang, your hand…
Choi Chiung has been arrested.
But…
Ms. Ko is seriously injured.
AUTHORIZED PERSONNEL ONLY
RESTRICTED AREA
[sobs]
Where have you been?
I said, where have you been?
[doctor] Any more delay, and she could be
permanently paralyzed.
We're operating right now.
-Let's get her under.
-[anesthesiologist] Yes, Doctor.
[♪ heartwarming music playing]
Honey.
I'm not late this time, am I?
Okay, let's get started.
Blade, please.
[anchor] New developments in
the kidnapping at a major local hospital.
The full story behind the kidnapping
and attempted murder
at a major hospital
is now coming to light.
[reporter 1]
Is it true that you planned the crime?
-[reporter 2] Any words for the victims?
-[reporter 3] When did you hatch the plan?
-[reporter 4] Do you admit to the crime?
-[reporter 5] Will you plead guilty?
[reporter 4] Do you have anything to say?
-[Detective Oh] Coming through.
-[reporter 6] Any comments?
[Detective Oh] Please make way.
[anchor] Police have identified
the hospital's vice director,
Choi, as the one who planned
and orchestrated the crime.
However, Choi has reportedly
denied all allegations.
-He's coming out!
-There he is!
[reporter 7] Any comments on the matter?
[anchor] Investigators say Noh Manhui,
who carried out the crime,
handed over a written confession
and audio recordings detailing the offense
to police before his arrest.
Noh insists he acted alone
and strongly denies that his wife,
Kim, had any part in it.
However, police believe
there's evidence that Kim conspired
in the kidnapping and false imprisonment,
and plan to refer her case
to the prosecutors first.
NOH MANHUI CLAIMS HIS WIFE IS INNOCENT
WOORI TOGETHER MEDICAL CENTER
FUND DONATION AGREEMENT
[Seyun] We have to make right what we can.
And you have to be the one to do it.
DIRECTOR KO DONGCHAN
WOORI TOGETHER MEDICAL CENTER
DISTINGUISHED SERVICE AWARD
SPINE CLINICAL RESEARCH FOUNDATION
[anchor 2] Dr. Ko Dongchan, director
of Woori Together Medical Center,
turned himself in to police this morning.
Ko reportedly acknowledged responsibility
for the illegal medical practices
and stated that he would fully
cooperate with the police investigation.
Dr. Ko, a leading figure
in spinal neurosurgery,
is accused of illegally obtaining
stem cells from aborted fetuses
and using them in surgeries
-to improve the success rate…
-[phone buzzing]
…of a highly anticipated spinal cord
reconstruction clinical trial.
Yes, hello?
STYLE
::cue()
I'm sorry to bother you again.
It's no problem.
Do you remember the video
you talked to us about?
The video of your husband
you saw in captivity.
Yes.
We recovered what seems to be
the original file
from the perp's computer.
We just need you to confirm
if it's the same as the one you saw.
Okay.
I'll give you a moment.
[door opens]
[door closes]
[Manhui] Sir, did you call for a driver?
[Taeju] I feel like I made the call
a second ago. You got here so quickly.
[Manhui] Well, I just happened to be
in the area, so I got here fast.
You must be exhausted, sir. Oh, here.
I got this for myself,
but you can have it.
Oh, thanks. I appreciate it.
[coughs]
[grunts]
[inhales]
Hey…
[Manhui] Yeah?
[Taeju] Have you ever…
lost a loved one?
[chuckles]
Well, yeah, of course.
But I mean, who hasn't?
No. Not like that.
Like…
Have you lost anyone that you truly love?
I'm always trying my absolute best
not to let that happen.
You see…
I've lost my little girl.
I should have been there for my wife.
But I didn't have the guts
to tell her the truth.
[inhales] Hmm.
So I couldn't be there.
[Manhui] I see.
Go on.
I want to tell my wife
the truth about everything,
but I worry she might break down
if she found out everything.
I can't bring myself to say anything.
[Manhui] But I mean,
don't you think things would get better
if you just talked to her about it?
No.
[exhales]
I can't let her live with the consequences
of the choices that I've made.
But you know,
there's a limit
to how much you can lie.
So…
I said we should get divorced.
Oh, no.
But she said she didn't want to.
Well…
She said she'd never do it.
Why's that?
Because it's what I want.
[sighs]
She doesn't want to
give me anything I want.
I'm all out of options now.
Anyway, that being said…
I want you to get rid of my wife.
What? What did you say?
I'll pay you, okay?
I'll pay you 300… No.
I'll pay you 500 million won. So please.
So you want me to get rid of your wife?
Seyun could…
STYLE
::cue()
She could never be happy
as long as she's with me.
So…
I want you…
to take my wife
out of my life.
So she won't be haunted by the truth…
or be lonely because of all my lies.
I just…
[inhales]
…I want her to stay in the dark…
and disappear…
[sniffles]
…from my life.
The further away she stays from me…
the happier she would be in life.
[sighs]
[footsteps approaching]
Did you get it checked out?
Yeah.
What did they say?
To keep going to therapy. They said
it should be back to normal soon.
And your work?
Can you still do surgeries?
I see.
[sighs]
It's fine. I'll be fine.
Stop saying you're fine.
This is clearly not fine.
I know how much it means to…
I mean it, I'm fine.
I can move it and all.
That's what matters.
[sighs]
You're always like this.
It wouldn't have gotten this bad
if you'd gotten surgery right away.
I watched…
that video of you.
I finally get it.
How you must have felt at the time.
You didn't want to get rid of me.
You wanted to protect me.
But that made things clearer for me.
We'll always be like this.
You'll hide things to protect me,
and I'll be left in the dark and get hurt.
That's why I'm going to let go of you.
Let's get divorced.
[♪ sad music playing]
It's not your fault, though.
I know.
And it's not your fault, either.
The way we love each other…
is just very different.
STYLE
::cue()
KANG TAEJU
NEUROSURGERY CLINIC
-[Taeju] Come in.
-[door opens]
CONSULTATION ROOM
Have you been doing
the exercise I taught you last time?
I did, but it just hurt more.
Pardon?
Well, that's why you have to do it.
My goodness, you and your nagging.
That's what you're here for, isn't it?
Make sure to receive
physical therapy, okay?
Grandma, you have to
actually do it this time.
All right. [groans]
-[grandchild] Thank you, Doctor.
-Okay, bye.
Take care, ma'am.
-[chuckles]
-[door closes]
[sighs]
SEOKGI CHUEOTANG
[mother] There it is.
-Here.
-Go on.
Why don't you come by more often?
How are things over there?
Don't you get lonely?
No, it's good.
You know, the patients are nice.
It's nice and quiet.
[Taeyeong] Geez.
Stop saying it's all good.
Mom's clearly worried about you.
-When will you grow up? [chuckles]
-[chuckles]
Oh, hey, Mom. This is for you.
What's all this?
You seem to get worse with every checkup.
Make sure you take these.
[gasps]
I was actually worried
because my numbers keep dropping.
You don't want a fracture
or a broken bone.
A lot of patients come in
after falling accidents.
-I got you a box, too.
-Really?
I see you've actually grown up. [chuckles]
I mean, it's about time
I took care of myself.
[mother] Okay, why don't we…
Yeah, let's take one together.
-Yeah?
-Here, take one.
-Okay.
-[chuckles]
-You too.
-Wow, me too?
Yes.
[liquid pouring]
There.
All right, let's take it.
-[giggling] Here's to our health!
-[chuckles]
-To our health!
[Taeyeong] Goodness.
Oh, welcome.
-[guest] Yeah, hi.
-This way.
Okay.
So, are you in touch at all?
Do you hear from her?
I'm sure she's doing fine.
[sighs]
You know, Mom,
a lot of women do come to see me.
What?
It's true.
It's just that
they're a bit older than you.
-They mostly come in with knee pain.
-[chuckles]
Goodness, you silly boy.
Well, it's good to see you
make jokes and laugh now.
[sighs] My goodness.
STYLE
::cue()
KANG HAYUN
MAY 20, 2022 - JANUARY 28, 2025
Hey, Hayun. Daddy's here.
How have you been?
WE WILL REMEMBER YOU
LOVE YOU, SWEETHEART
[coughs]
How have you been?
Good.
That's good.
What about you?
I'm getting there.
I'm going to take a walk.
Okay.
Can I walk with you?
Sure.
[♪ "Us, Now" playing]
THE HUSBAND
THANK YOU FOR WATCHING THE HUSBAND
Translated by Hyun Sik Yoon